<!-- ------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
<!--                                                                     -->
<!--  intro.xml             KAN documentation             Chris Wensley  -->
<!--                                                    & Anne Heyworth  -->
<!-- ------------------------------------------------------------------- -->

<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<Chapter Label="intro">
<Heading>Introduction</Heading>

The &kan; package started out as part of Anne Heyworth's thesis 
<Cite Key="anne-thesis" />, and was designed to compute 
induced actions of categories (see also <Cite Key="BrHe" />). 
<P/>
This version of &kan; only provides functions for the computation of
normal forms of representatives of double cosets of finitely presented groups, 
and is made available in support of the paper <Cite Key="BrGhHeWe" />. 
Existing methods for computing double cosets in &GAP; are described 
in <Cite Key="SteveL" />.
<P/>
The package is loaded into &GAP; with the command
<Example>
<![CDATA[
gap> LoadPackage( "kan" ); 
]]>
</Example>

The package may be obtained as a compressed tar file 
<File>kan-version.number.tar.gz</File>
by ftp from one of the following sites: 
<List>
<Item>
the &kan; GitHub site: 
<URL>https://github.com/gap-packages.github.io/kan/</URL>. 
</Item>
<Item>
any &GAP; archive, e.g. 
<URL>https://www.gap-system.org/Packages/packages.html</URL>; 
</Item>
</List>
The package also has a GitHub repository at: 
<URL>https://github.com/gap-packages/kan/</URL>.
<P/>

Some of the functions in the &Automata; package 
are used to compute word acceptors and regular expressions 
for the languages they accept.
<P/>
The <Package>KBMag</Package> package is also used 
to compute a word acceptor of a group <C>G</C> 
when <C>G</C> has no finite rewriting system. 
If <Package>KBMag</Package> is not available 
(the user is not on a UNIX system, or the C-programs have not been compiled), 
the file <File>dckbmag.gi</File> will not be read, 
so methods for the functions detailed in section 2.4.1 will not be available. 
<P/>
Once the package is loaded, it is possible to check the installation 
is correct by running a test file of the manual examples with the
following command. 
(The test file itself is <F>tst/fulltest.tst</F> or <F>tst/parttest.tst</F>, 
depending whether or not <Package>KBMag</Package> is available.) 
<Example>
<![CDATA[
gap> ReadPackage( "kan", "tst/testall.g" );
#I  Testing /Applications/gap/my-dev/pkg/kan/tst/fulltest.tst
#I  No errors detected while testing package kan
true
]]>
</Example>
<P/>
The information parameter <C>InfoKan</C> takes default value <C>0</C>.
When raised to a higher value, additional information is printed out.
<P/> 
Once the package is loaded, the manual <Code>doc/manual.pdf</Code> 
can be found in the documentation folder. 
The <Code>html</Code> versions, with or without MathJax, 
may be rebuilt as follows. 
<P/>
<Example>
<![CDATA[
gap> InfoLevel( InfoKan );
0
gap> ReadPackage( "kan, "makedoc.g" ); 
]]>
</Example>
<P/>
Please send bug reports, suggestions and other comments to the second author,
or use the GitHub issue tracker at 
<URL>https://github.com/gap-packages/kan/issues/new</URL>.  
<P/>
Additional information can be found on the
<E>Computational Higher-dimensional Discrete Algebra</E> website at
<URL>https://github.com/cdwensley</URL>. 

</Chapter>
